Phillip Francis

Software Developer

Reliable and punctual Software Developer with experience in a team environment. With skills in CSS, JavaScript, React, and a few other languages. My experience with companies like Cintas and Fedex has shown the importance a single employee has in the success of a company. Which motivates me to be the best I can be for the overall success of not only myself but also the people around me.

Contact

Address

Philadelphia, Pennsylvannia, 19120

Phone

(215) 255-5388

E-mail

phillipmfrancis93@yahoo.co

Skills

Javascript

React/Redux

IMTH

CSS

Git

PostgreSQL

Node.js

REST

Express.js

Bootstrap

Work History

2018-01 -2020-03

Warehouse Associate

Cintas, Philadelphia, Pennsylvannia

- Helped team efforts by backing up fellow warehouse workers in managing incoming and outgoing products.
- Processed incoming trucks, working to unload, stage, and store merchandise smoothly.
- Processed new stock by inputting information into system and adding labels.

2014-01 -2017-01

Warehouse Associate

FedEx, Philadelphia, PA

- Carried out day-day-day duties accurately and efficiently.
- Improved operations through consistent hard work and dedication.
- Demonstrated respect, friendliness and willingness to help wherever needed.

Education

2021-03 -2021-06

Software Development

Digitalcrafts - Atlanta, GA

Immersive Full-stack Engineering bootcamp covering a multitude of languages including HTML, CSS, JS and others like Python. We also were taught server side languages like Postgres, Express, Node and frameworks like React/Redux

also Bootstrap.

2020-08 -2020-12

Web Development

Juno College of Technology - Toronto, ON, Canada

I took two separate courses at Juno from August to December. The first course was focused on front-end development and solidified the fundamentals of HTML, CSS, and responsive development. The second course was a Javascript course building on my understanding of HTML and CSS using Javascript to add more advanced and exciting elements.

Projects

Drop Thoughts, https://github.com/Phillip215/Drop_Thoughts

- Made with HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, React, and hosted on Supabase
- Our application allows users to type in how they are feeling. The users input will append to the journal page. The implemented tone analyzer API determines the user's mood based on keywords from their input and adds the mood to the database and their mood chart.
- This was a group project where I was tasked to handle the functionality of our application specifically the transfer of data through the different pages in our application
- With more time we wanted to add a customized calender so a person can view there moods in a more broad view

City-Livin, https://github.com/Phillip215/City-livin

- Made with HTML5, CSS, JavaScript and using REST
- This was a solo frontend project where I decided to make a website that gives you information on life in different cities
- It has rankings on day to day life on one page while on another you can find upcoming

- events in a city near you
- With more time I wanted to finish my third page which only shows random photo's of scenery when I originally wanted it to be scenery based on the city the user searched